RG 004:049, Enfield Probate Court
Connecticut State Library
Enfield Probate Court records
1831-1971, bulk 1831-1922
Connecticut State Library
Connecticut. Probate Court (Enfield District)
26.75 cubic feet
Record books, 1831-1922, 1962-1971; Probate files, 1831-1898.
RG004_049
1945-005 and 2011-052
Historical Note
Enfield, Hartford County, Town established in 1683, Parent Town: Part of Massachusetts until May 1749
The Enfield Probate District was constituted May 26, 1831 from the East Windsor Probate District. The Enfield Probate District merged with the Stafford Probate District on January 5, 2011 to create the North Central Connecticut Probate District which serves the municipalities of Enfield, Somers, Stafford, and Union.
Town of Enfield, Probate District chronology:
1683 - May 1749, Hampshire County Massachusetts Jurisdiction
May 1749 - May 1782, Hartford District
May 1782 - May 25, 1831, East Windsor District
May 26, 1831 - January 4, 2011, Enfield District
January 5, 2011 - Present, North Central Connecticut District
For Probate Court contact information and hours of operation see,.
Scope and Content
Probate record books, Volumes 1-24, 1831-1922, one unnumbered bond book, 1881-1899, and volume 74, bonds, 1962-1971. Contact the probate court to access original record books after Volume 24. See Alternative Form Available note below.
Probate files, 1831-1898. Probate files may consist of estates, conservatorships, guardianships, commitments, and insolvencies.
Inventory control book, 1831-1898 (coverage). Also known as the Godard Digest, it is a list of probate files transferred to the Connecticut State Library. It was compiled at the Connecticut State Library under the direction of State Librarian George S. Godard.
Arrangement
Record books are numbered consecutively from 1 to 24. There is also one unnumbered bond volume and volume 74, which is also bonds.
Probate files are arranged alphabetically in one series.
Other Finding Aid
Record Books: Index cards for the record books have been scanned. Ask History and Genealogy staff for assistance.
Probate Files: The Probate Estate Papers Index, located in the index corridor adjacent to the History and Genealogy Reading Room, has two parts, a general index covering most of the state, and a Hartford Probate District index covering Hartford and some surrounding towns, 1820-1920. The index cards are arranged alphabetically by individual's last name and first names. The cards have the individual's name, town of residence, probate district, and list of items contained in the estate packet. To request retrieval of an estate packet, copy at least the estate name, file date, and probate district name from the index card. The probate files in accession 1945-005 are represented in this index.
Index Terms
Subjects:
Probate records -- Connecticut - Enfield
Places:
Enfield (Conn.)
Restrictions on Access
Researchers should first consult use copies when available. See Alternate Form Available Section below.
Accession 2011-052, Record books, 1831-1922 are stored at an off-site facility and therefore may not be available on a same-day basis.
See the policy.
Alternative Form Available
Record books, Volumes 1-2, 5, 7, 9, 10, 12-15, 17-21, 1831-1916; probate files 1831-1915; and inventory control book (Godard Digest) were microfilmed by the Genealogical Society of Utah and are available for use in the History and Genealogy reading room or through the.
Provenance
The probate files in accession 1945-005 were transferred to the Connecticut State Library on the following dates (with date span of files): February 26, 1945 (1831-1998).
The record books in accession 2011-052 were transferred to the Connecticut State Library on November 22, 2010.
Container List
- Record books, 1831-1922; 13.5 cubic feet (26 volumes); 2011-052
  - Records, 1831-1844 (Volume 1)
  - Records, 1844-1850 (Volume 2)
  - Records, 1850-1856 (Volume 3)
  - Orders and decrees, 1855-1869 (Volume 4)
    On spine: "Records"
  - Records, 1856-1874 (Volume 5)
  - Orders and decrees, 1869-1878 (Volume 6)
  - Records, 1873-1884 (Volume 7)
  - Orders and decrees, 1878-1887 (Volume 8)
  - Guardians and wards, 1882-1891 (Volume 9)
  - Records, 1884-1893 (Volume 10)
  - Orders and decrees, 1887-1894 (Volume 11)
  - Records, 1893-1896 (Volume 12)
  - Records, 1896-1899 (Volume 13)
  - Records, 1899-1903 (Volume 14)
  - Records, 1903-1905 (Volume 15)
  - Bonds, 1903-1922 (Volume 16)
    On spine: "Records". Label on spine: "B:
  - Records, 1905-1908 (Volume 17)
  - Records, 1908-1911 (Volume 18)
  - Records, 1911-1913 (Volume 19)
  - Records, 1913-1915 (Volume 20)
  - Records, 1914-1916 (Volume 21)
  - Records, 1916-1917 (Volume 22)
  - Records, 1917-1919 (Volume 23)
  - Records, 1919-1921 (Volume 24)
  - Bonds, 1881-1899 (Volume unnumbered)
  - Bonds, 1962-1971 (Volume 74)
- Probate files, 1831-1898; 13.25 cubic feet; 1945-005
  - Abbe - Burbank, J. (Drawer 1)
  - Burbank, J. - Gallagher (Drawer 2)
  - Gallo - Gorman (Drawer 3)
  - Gowdy - Harper (Drawer 4)
  - Harrington - Hibbard (Drawer 5)
  - Hickman - Kelliher (Drawer 6)
  - Kellogg - Kingsbury, C. (Drawer 7)
  - Kingsbury, D. - Lewis (Drawer 8)
  - Liddell - MacAviney (Drawer 9)
  - MacCarthy - Maher (Drawer 10)
  - Mallard - Mitchell (Drawer 11)
  - Mixter - O'Brien (Drawer 12)
  - O'Callahan - Parker (Drawer 13)
  - Parsons - Patterson (Drawer 14)
  - Payne - Phelps (Drawer 15)
  - Phillips - Prior (Drawer 16)
  - Prudden - Robbins (Drawer 17)
  - Roberts - Slamon (Drawer 18)
  - Slater - Stewart (Drawer 19)
  - Stillman - Taylor (Drawer 20)
  - Terry - Tryon (Drawer 21)
  - Tullar - Watton (Drawer 22)
  - Weir - Wood (Drawer 23)
  - Winnervisser - Zeist (Drawer 24)
- Inventory control book, 1831-1898; T003073
  Index of the probate files in accession 1945-005
  Also known as the Godard Digest